Guide to the Keith Fleming Papers Relating to Edmund White
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Keith Fleming Papers Relating to Edmund White
1993-1999
YCAL MSS 887
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.46
(4 boxes)
Fleming, Keith
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Boxes 2-3 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 4 (computer disk): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Keith Fleming
Keith Fleming, American writer, is the author of The Boy with the Thorn in His Side (New York: W. Morrow, 2000) and Original Youth: The Real Story of Edmund White's Boyhood (San Francisco, Calif.: Green Candy Press, 2003). Keith Fleming is Edmund White's nephew.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: I. Drafts, 1993-1999. II. Research Materials, 1995, undated.
Scope and Contents
The Keith Fleming Papers Relating to Edmund White contain manuscripts, research files, biographical material, photographs, sound recordings of interviews, and electronic media created and collected by Fleming while working on the biography Original Youth: The Real Story of Edmund White's Boyhood.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Keith Fleming on the Eugene G. O'Neill Memorial Fund, 2001.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century -- Archives; Biographers -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiovisual materials -- United States -- 20th Century; Born digital -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographs -- United States -- 20th Century; Photographic prints -- United States -- 20th Century; Audiocassettes -- United States -- 20th Century; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Biographers -- United States -- 20th Century; LGBTQ resource; Fleming, Keith; White, Edmund, 1940-; Keith Fleming
- Drafts, 1993-1999
  - Completely New Beginning: 1970-1976, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Making of a Gay Writer: 1977-1982, 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Exile from the Plague: 1983-1989, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Living Posthumously: 1990-, 1994-1996 (Box 1)
  - That Shitty Gay Life: 1960-1969, 1995-1999 (Box 1)
  - Outline, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 1)
  - The Birthday Boy: 1940-1951, 1995 (Box 1)
  - First Sex and Being Popular: 1952-1955, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Prep School: 1956-1958, 1995-1996; 2 (Box 1)
  - Three Musketeers, 1995 (Box 1)
  - College: 1958-1962, 1993-1995 (Box 1)
- Research Materials, 1995, undated
  - 1. Biographies, undated (Box 1)
  - 2. Loose material on people interviewed including bio info by others, undated (Box 1)
  - 3. Loose material I've gathered on Ed, undated (Box 1)
  - 4. Names and addresses of interviewees, undated (Box 1)
  - 5. Questions for Ed, undated (Box 1)
  - 6. Photographs (Don Daskais, Cranbrook Grounds, undated; 5 (Box 1)
  - 7. To be read of Ed's (or on him), undated (Box 1)
  - 8. General gay stuff, undated (Box 1)
  - 9. To be investigated (e.g. fact checking), undated (Box 1)
  - 10. Untranscribed parts of White interviews, undated (Box 1)
  - 11-13. [Chapters one-three] - empty, undated (Box 1)
  - 14. Chapter four, undated (Box 1)
  - 15-16. [Chapter five] - empty and [Maria Tulokas] - empty, undated (Box 1)
  - 17. Movies to See, undated (Box 1)
  - 18. Grants, 1995 (Box 1)
  - 19. Reading list, undated (Box 1)
  - 20. Reviews of Ed's books, undated (Box 1)
  - 21. Anti-Freud psychology, undated (Box 1)
  - 22. Letters, undated (Box 1)
  - 23. [Misc. (other stuff in my life)] - empty, undated (Box 1)
  - 24. Indexes to Ed's writing, undated (Box 1)
  - 25. Copies of my letters to people, undated (Box 1)
  - 26-27. [empty] and [My Life in the Basement] - empty, undated (Box 1)
  - 28. Editorial notes to myself, undated (Box 1)
  - 29. Afterward, undated (Box 1)
  - 30. Defending my manuscript, undated (Box 1)
  - 31. Maps, undated (Box 1)
  - Unsorted correspondence, notes, and writings, undated; 5 (Box 1)
- Computer media and Audiovisual Materials
  Conditions Governing Access
  Boxes 2-3 (audiocassettes) and Box 4 (computer disk): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - Audiovisual Materials, 37
    Boxes 2-3 (audiocassettes): Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    Scope and Contents
    Interviews recorded on audiocassettes.
    - Charles Burch (with Pat Lamson) - 3 and 4, 1995 September 22; 1; 01:24:24; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617031)
      Audiovisual material. Restricted fragile. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
    - Charles Burch, 1995 September 22; 1; 01:23:24; High background noise can be heard on the tape. The program ends abruptly. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617049)
    - Charles Burch - 3, 1995 October 7; 1; 00:52:24; The program ends abruptly. Buzz and static can be heard. A hum can also be heard on the tape. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617023)
    - Interview with Margaret Fleming - 1 and 2, 1995 January 22-Februrary 7; 1; 01:31:40; The program begins and ends abruptly. A hum and a high amount of buzz can be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617080)
    - Margaret Fleming - 3 and 4, 1995 February 7-19; 1; 01:34:01; The program begins and ends abruptly. A buzz can be heard on the tape. Static and hum can also be heard. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617098)
    - Margaret Fleming - 5 and 6, 1995 February 19-26; 1; 01:24:45; The program is distorted at times. A buzz can be heard on the tape. The program ends abruptly. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617072)
    - Margaret Fleming, 1995 March 5; 1; 00:33:11; The program is distorted at times. A high amount of buzz can be heard. The program ends abruptly. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617064)
    - John Hunting, 1995 September 15; 1; 01:07:50; The program begins abruptly. A high amount of buzz can be heard. The program is distorted at times. A high amount of hum is on the tape. High frequency noise can be heard. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617106)
    - Ed White / Tom McGuane, 1995 November 12-27; 1; 01:17:05; The program is distorted at times. Static and hum can be heard on the tape. A buzz can also be heard. The program ends abruptly. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617114)
    - Penny McLeod (Adrian Weatley), 1996 September 29; 1; 01:10:06; The program begins and ends abruptly. Static and buzz can be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617122)
    - Patrick Merla, 1995 January 24; 1; 00:40:04; The program begins abruptly. The program is distorted at times. A high amount of hum and hiss can be heard. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617130)
    - Sue White and George Newman III, 1995 April 8-17; 1; 01:16:09; The program begins and ends abruptly. A high amount of hum can be heard. There is a buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617148)
    - Stanley Redfern, 1995 August 1; 1; 01:14:25; The program begins abruptly. There is a buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617155)
    - David Schwartz, 1995 August 5; 1; 01:15:54; The program begins and ends abruptly. A buzz can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617163)
    - Marilyn Schaefer and Jean Snow (White), 1995 March 4-May 1; 1; 01:33:43; The program begins and ends abruptly. Static and hum can be heard. There is a buzz on the tape as well. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617171)
    - Johanna Tabin, 1995 May 4; 1; 01:02:27; The program begins and ends abruptly. Static and hum can be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617197)
    - Steve Turner, 1995 March 8; 1; 00:29:54; The program begins abruptly. A high amount of buzz can be heard. The program is distorted at times. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617189)
    - Ed White, 1995 Jul 13-19; 1; 01:19:42; The program begins and ends abruptly. Static andd buzz can be heard on the tape. A hum can also be heard. (Box 2, Item barcode 39002104617056)
      Notes indicate University of Michigan days and talk of college funds.
    - Stephen Turner, 1991 May 21; 1; 00:23:48; The program begins and ends abruptly. The program is distorted at times. Volume decreases over the course of the tape. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617205)
    - Helen White and Ed phone message re: my memoirs, 1995 April 21, 1999 October 2; 1; 01:19:42; The program begins abruptly. There is a buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617213)
    - Laura Torrespico and Ed White, 1995 March 31-April 5; 1; 01:20:56; The program begins and ends abruptly. There is buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617221)
    - John Purcell and Ed White, 1995 February 6-March 10; 1; 01:33:26; The program is distorted at times. High background noise can be heard. A high amount of buzz and static is on the tape. Audio in the right channel is silent for the first nine minutes. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617239)
      Music can be heard for the first six seconds of the tape. Interviews related to the collection run from 00:06-16:42. A mix of other content, including a radio broadcast of an NBA game, runs from 16:43-46:33. Interviews pick up again at 46:34.
    - Ed White and follow-up on chapters 1-3, 1995 May 16-June 5; 1; 01:33:43; The program begins and ends abruptly. There is hum on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617247)
    - Ed White interview, childhood, 1995 January 17; 1; 01:34:17; The program is distorted at times. There is static on the tape. Audio in the right channel is silent for the first 15 minutes. The program ends abruptly. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617254)
      Interview and commentary runs until 19:41 on the tape. It is followed by a music mix. The interview with Ed White picks up again at 47:10.
    - Ed White interview, early adolescence Follow-up Questions, Pre-Cranbrook - 5 and 6, 1995 January 25-February 2; 1; 01:34:24; The program begins abruptly. There is buzz, static and hum on the tape. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617270)
    - Ed White follow up questions, pre-Cranbrook; more Ed White follow-up, 1995 February 2-April 14; 1; 01:27:38; The program is distorted at times. The program ends abruptly. A high amount of buzz can be heard. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617262)
    - Ed White childhood delusions of grandeur, 1995 February 8; 1; 01:35:18; The program begins and ends abruptly. A high amount of buzz can be heard. The program is distorted at times. Audio in the right channel is silent at times. There is an occasional warble in the last 47 minutes of the tape. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617296)
      A mix of music, from the Beatles and others, can be heard from the beginning of the tape to 47:45.
    - Ed White interview - 3 and 4, 1995 January 18-25; 1; 01:34:00; The program is distorted at times. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617288)
    - Ed White, 1996 January 26; 1; 00:29:40; The program begins abruptly. There is buzz and static on the tape. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617304)
    - Ed White, 1995 March 14-16; 1; 01:44:45; The program begins and ends abruptly. There is buzz, hum and static on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617320)
    - Ed White (reading story at end), 1995 March 17-23; 1; 01:34:43; There is buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. Hum and static can be heard. There is a high amount of hiss in the last 42 and a half minutes. The program ends abruptly. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617312)
    - Ed White, 1995 May 27-June 2; 1; 01:23:28; The program begins and ends abruptly. There is buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. A hum can be heard. There is a high amount of hiss that can be heard in the last 47 minutes of the program. High background noise can be heard on the tape. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617338)
    - Ed White, Cranbrook, 1995 June 2-5; 1; 01:29:37; There is hum and static on the tape. The program is distorted at times. The program ends abruptly. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617346)
    - Ed White, 1995 June 18-20; 1; 01:31:02; The program is distorted at times. There is a buzz on the tape. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617353)
    - Ed White, 1995 July 2-November 12; 1; 01:24:29; There is a high amount of buzz on the tape. The program is distorted at times. A hum is heard on the tape. The program begins and ends abruptly. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617361)
    - Consulting Ed on ms, 1996; 1; 01:34:07; A high amount of buzz can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. A high amount of hum is on the tape. Audio in the right channel is silent from about 47:01-1:07:01. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617379)
      A mix of Beatles music and George Harrison songs play from about 1:07:38 until the end of the tape.
    - Ed White, 1995 June 22-July 2; 1; 01:33:25; The program begins and ends abruptly. A hum and buzz can be heard on the tape. The program is distorted at times. (Box 3, Item barcode 39002104617387)
  - Computer media
    - Biography of Ed White's Youth by Keith Fleming, 2001-ycal-1119-b-0001; 1 (Box 4)
      Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.